STEVE BATCUP

07490 787696

steve.batcup@gmail.com

https://www.stevebatcup.dev

https://github.com/stevebatcup

Profile

Hello! I'm Steve Batcup, i'm a full-stack web developer and project manager. I have experience with **Ruby on Rails**, **Flutter**, **AngularJS**, **Docker**, **Firebase**, **Ubuntu Linux** and more. I try to follow the ethos of keeping code as clear and concise as possible.

For the best part of my career I have worked as a Senior Developer and allround tech solutions guy for two successful web businesses as a permanent employee and as a freelancer.

After a Covid-19 redundancy in March this year I decided it was time to up-skill before returning to the job market. I set about learning some new important skills.

As a developer in 2020 it's near impossible to have experience in all of the available tech stacks around. But after 15 years in the business I've developed the confidence to learn whatever tech is required for the job at hand.

I'm now available for both permanent and contract work and am ready to hit the ground running.

Experience

Director, SV Batcup Ltd - 2018-Present

Whilst continuing to work with *Muddy Matches* but moving to a contract basis rather than as a full-time employee, I also took on a long term contract with a startup called *Quad Journal Ltd* building and maintaining a media platform for their vision of a cross-political exchange of ideas: www.thearticle.com using Ruby on Rails.

Again I was the sole-developer and tech lead on this project.

My contract with *Muddy Matches* ended in Dec 2019 and my contract with *Quad Journal* is due to end soon.

Web Manager, Muddy Matches Ltd - 2011-2018

I was the all-round-go-to tech person at this successful countrywide dating website geared at rural singles: www.muddymatches.co.uk.

Here I was the sole-developer and project manager all rolled into one. All tech decisions were now mine to make. Main MM website was built in PHP (Zend) but various other tools and internal admin-systems were built using Ruby on Rails.

Developer, Evolving Ltd — 2008-2011

Like most web-devs I cut my development teeth at a marketing agency. *Evolving*, based in Bedford, had a series of medium profile clients such as *David* *Lloyd*, *Weatherspoons*, *Yo Sushi* and *Carluccios*. Here I learned how to work to client specification at a fast pace. All sites were built using an in-house PHP framework and HTML/CSS front-ends.

Developer, WillWork4Food Web Designs — 2005-2008

The start of my web-dev career! Small brochure websites for local businesses. Taking on the challenges and learning on the job. HTML and CSS which then progressed to PHP with MySQL.

Education

Coventry University - Music Composition B.A (2:1), 1998-2001

Skills / Technologies

- Ruby on Rails (incl v6.0)
- Flutter (Android, iOS and Web)
- Firebase (Firestore, Cloud Functions, Cloud Build/Run, Hosting, etc)
- Docker
- Javascript: AngularJS, Coffeescript, etc
- PHP: Zend framework, etc
- HTML/CSS: Sass, etc
- MySQL and Postgresql
- AWS: EC2, ELB, WAF, Cloudwatch, Elasticache, SES, RDS (Aurora)
- Ubuntu linux server management (+ Capistrano for Rails deployment)
- Sidekiq/Redis for Rails background tasks
- Administrate: for quick-build rails admin systems
- Git: Github, branches, etc
- Payment APIs: Chargebee, Stripe, Worldpay, Sagepay, Paypal
- Unity/C#

Hobbies/Interests

I play drum kit, specialising in Jazz, involved in an ensemble at a weekend Jazz School. I also enjoy reading Science Fiction novels (no surprise there for a tech!).

References

- Lucy Rand Director at Muddy Matches Ltd lucy@muddymatches.co.uk
- Stephen Rand Director at Quad Journal Ltd stephen.rand@thearticle.com

Please see my portfolio website https://stevebatcup.dev for more details.